Louis J. Budd Papers and compilation of Mark Twain Resources, 1980-2008, undated
Elmira College
- SERIES 3: MARK TWAIN INTERVIEWS, undated; This series compiled by Louis J. Budd contains photocopies and transcriptions of Mark Twain interviews. Dates reflect the date of the original article and not the date of reproduction. This series contains Budd’s original folder headings and is arranged ch
  - New York World, New York Times -- "Mark Twain Moved to Postpone Funeral/Younger Now By 7 Years, He Says, and Changes Mind about Dying" -- "Clemens briefly waxes enthusiastic about his current visit to England", July 13, 1907
  - London Morning Leader, London Tribune -- "Two Mark Twains/One of them Leave England/Mark Twain's Farewell", July 13, 1907 - July 16, 1907
  - New York Evening World -- "English Know a Joke/Mark Twain's Wireless Message from the Sea/Reports that His Ship Tore Off the Bowsprit of an Unknown Bark in the Fog" -- "Clemens comments briefly on a number of topics including the British sense of humor", July 22, 1907
  - New York American -- "Twain Home with English Jokes at 30 Cents a Word" -- "Much chaffing about the Ascot cup; Clemens defends British sense of humor", July 23, 1907
  - New York Herald -- "Dr. Mark Twain, Pelted, Home Again" -- "Clemens jokes about his visit to England and the return voyage", July 23, 1907
  - New York SUN -- "Mark Twain Comes in White" -- "Clemens comments on recent stories about his English visit; chaffs about old age and his new rate for 'stories and jokes'", July 23, 1907
  - New York Times -- "Mark Twain Home in Good Humor", July 23, 1907
  - New York Tribune -- "Twain Glad He's Back" -- "Somewhat fewer quotations, July 23, 1907
  - New York Evening World -- "Mark Twain Recalls Happy Days in Fresco" -- "Clemens briefly recalls 'dear, dead Bohemian days of long ago'", July 23, 1907
  - New York World -- "Mark Twain Home, Captive of Little Girl" -- "Story devotes much space to young fellow-passenger Dorothy Quick", July 23, 1907
  - New York World -- "My Hand Interviews with Mark Twain and Thomas Edison" -- "Clemens submits to having his palm read; in a mellow mood he comments on current situation and age", August 25, 1907
  - New York Press -- "Mark Twain's Ideal Pipe" -- "Quoted from 'an interview the other day' seems genuine; not important but characteristic", September 15, 1907
  - Great Thoughts -- "A Prince of Humorists" -- "Long with much padding, many passages that may well come from Mark Twain's writings and commentary", October 5, 1907
  - Brooklyn Daily Eagle -- "Mark Twain on the Scope of the Children's Theater/What it Means to American Citizenship and Education" -- "Besides praising East Side theater for children, Clemens talks about the importance of enunciation, and of raising esthetic taste among immigrants; he also discourses on responsible citizenship vs. jingoistic patriotism, November 24, 1907
  - New York American, SUN, Times, World, Tribune -- "Rogers is Busted--Twain" -- "Clemens jokes broadly about supposed poverty of H.H. Rogers", February 23, 1908
  - New York American, New York Herald, SUN, Times, World -- "Return from Bermuda/Mark Twain Faced Two Perils/Going to Make Less Noise/Mark Twain Gets a Sea Souse/Back from Bermuda with H.H. Rogers/Big Wave Loan to Rogers", April 14, 1908
  - New York American -- "Twain Says He Told Her 'Book a Mistake Twain's Daughter Talks About Him'", 1908-09-27, 1908-06-03
  - Boston Herald -- "Death of Roger/Mark Twain, Rockefeller, and Others Pay Tribute to Dead", May 19, 1909 - May 20, 1909
  - Baltimore News -- "Twain Puts Blame on the Typesetter", June 10, 1909
  - Baltimore Star -- "Twain Pokes Fun at Union Station and Pities City, June 11, 1909
  - Baltimore American -- "Why Not Baltimore?", June 12, 1909
  - New York American, Danbury News(?) -- "Mark Twain Has a Tobacco Heart/Mark Twain Cited for Awful Tobacco Habit/Mark Twain Smokes/The Psychology of the Tobacco Habit/Two Uncollected Twain Writings Found in British-Authored Books" -- "Clemens grumbles a little about interviewers but talks almost solely about his doctor's orders to reduce smoking and about the criticism of his having smoking while waiting for the Oxford ceremony", August 3, 1909
  - New York World, New York Tribune -- "Samuel Clemens Interviews Himself at Clara's Wedding/Mark Twain Prepares Interview and Sketches Guest, October, 1909
  - The Lounger -- "Clara's Wedding", December 7, 1909
  - New York American, SUN, Times, Tribune, Herald, World -- Mark Twain Returns from Bermuda", December 21, 1909
  - New York Herald, SUN, Times, Tribune, Evening World -- "Mark Twain Leaves NYC for Bermuda" -- "Several brief indirect quotations on Clemens's health", January 6, 1910
  - New York World -- "Mark Twain Returns Hastily to Bermuda" -- "Clemens Comments on his health and his solace in smoking cigars", January 6, 1910
  - Human Life -- "Mark Twain Back in Feeble Health/Mark Twain at Bermuda/The Venerable Prince of Humorists Who Has Been Seeking Rest and Seclusion in the British Isles" -- "Mark Twain staying with the Allens; visitor is slow to get to main business and is gushy; nothing of consequence gets said, but this may be the last interview with a very sick man", May, 1910
  - Chicago Inter-Ocean -- "Mark Twain's Boyhood (Jane Clemens)" -- "Mrs. Clemens lay the foundation for two legends about the boyhood of Clemens: his promises in the prescience of his father's coffin and his later promise never to drink intoxicants", April 5, 1911
  - New York Evening Post, Parade Magazine -- "Mark Twain's Daughter", 1931-01, 1960-04-24
- SERIES 4: MARK TWAIN REVIEWS, undated; This series is a compilation of reviews of Mark Twain’s works compiled by Lou Budd and is arranged alphabetically by title
  - Adam's Diary -- 1904 review copies, undated
  - Adventures of Huckleberry Finn -- photocopies and transcripts from 1884-1896, undated
  - Adventures of Tom Sawyer -- photocopies and transcripts from 1876-1877, undated
  - American Claimant -- review photocopies from 1892-1897, undated
  - Burlesque Autobiography -- photocopies and transcripts from 1871, undated
  - Captain Stormfield's Visit to Heaven -- photocopies from 1909 and 1910 reviews, undated
  - Christian Science -- photocopies and transcriptions from 1907, undated
  - Connecticut Yankee in King Author's Court -- photocopies and transcripts from 1889-1896, undated
  - A Dog's Tale -- photocopies from 1904-1905, contains an unrelated photograph, undated
  - Double-Barreled Detective -- photocopies and transcriptions from 1902, undated
  - Editorial: Wild Oats -- photocopies from 1905 reviews, undated
  - English as She Taught It -- photocopies from 1887 reviews, undated
  - Eve's Diary -- photocopies from 1906 reviews, undated
  - Following the Equator -- photocopies from 1897-1898 reviews, undated
  - The Gilded Age -- photocopies from 1874 reviews, undated
  - Hadleyburg-American -- photocopies from 1900 reviews, undated
  - Hadleyburg-British -- photocopies from 1900 reviews, undated
  - Horse's Tale -- photocopies from 1907-1908 reviews, undated
  - How to Tell a Story -- photocopies from 1897 and 1907 reviews, undated
  - Innocents Abroad (1) -- photocopies and transcripts from 1889-1890 reviews, undated
  - Innocents Abroad (2) -- photocopies and transcripts from 1889-1890 reviews, undated
  - Joan of Arc -- photocopies from 1896-1897 reviews, undated
  - The Jumping Frog of Calaveres County -- photocopies from 1867, undated
  - King Leopold's Soliloquy -- photocopies from 1905-1907 reviews, undated
  - Life on the Mississippi -- photocopies from 1883-1886 reviews, undated
  - Merry Tales -- photocopies from 1892 reviews, undated
  - Mysterious Stranger -- photocopies from 1916-1917 reviews, undated
  - The Prince and the Pauper -- photocopies from 1881-1897 reviews, undated
  - Puddin' Head Wilson -- photocopies from 1894-1895 reviews, undated
  - Punch, Brothers, Punch -- Photocopies from 1878 reviews, undated
  - Roughing It -- photocopies from 1872-1873 reviews, undated
  - Scrap-Book -- photocopies from 1877 and 1879 reviews, undated
  - Screamers/A Curious Dream -- photocopies from 1872 reviews, undated
  - Is Shakespeare Dead? -- photocopies from 1909 reviews, undated
  - Sketches, New and Old -- photocopies from 1875-1875 reviews, undated
  - Speeches [1910 Edition] -- photocopies and transcriptions from 1910 reviews, undated
  - Stolen White Elephant -- photocopies from 1882 reviews, undated
  - Tom Sawyer Abroad -- photocopies from 1894 and 1897 reviews, undated
  - Tom Sawyer Detective -- photocopies from 1896-1897 reviews, undated
  - A Tramp Abroad -- photocopies from 1879-1898 reviews, undated
  - A True Story Repeated Word for Word as I Heard It -- photocopies from 1877, undated
  - What is Man? -- photocopies from 1910-1918 reviews, undated
  - $30,000 Bequest -- photocopies from 1906-1907 reviews, undated
  - $1,000,000 Banknote -- photocopies from 1893 reviews, undated
  - Bibliographic cards for reviews, undated
  - Bibliographic cards for reviews (2), undated